Nothing is too crazy and also nothing is
too ugly. There is this famous saying
like make ugly ads. I think we invented
that and I believe in that 100% because
people don't want the TV shots at any
point that they want something that
catches them on the first glance. You
don't remember these skinny girls that
were working out obviously, but you do
remember something that shocks you and
that it's completely about taking the
person out of the grid of like of
scrolling your uh feed. Sometimes your
feed is so pretty that you need
something ugly to take your attention
from it.
>> Hello, I'm your host David Bernard. My
guest today is Julia Lennox. Working
across some of the biggest apps on the
planet, including Betterme, Replica, and
Solid Starts. Julia has spent a decade
doing one thing, growing apps. On the
podcast, I talk with Julia about why
founders belong in the marketing
trenches more often. What makes ugly ads
perform so well and why stable ad
performance is actually a red flag?
Quick programming note before we start
the podcast. Julia will be joining me on
YouTube live on July 30th, 9:00 a.m.
Pacific, 1800 Central European time.
I've heard from so many of you over the
years that you love the podcast, but you
end up in your car or on a walk just
shouting into the void, "What about this
or what about that?" So, now's your
chance. Take some notes as you listen to
the podcast. Listen carefully and join
us on July 30th to ask Ulia some
questions. Hey, Ulia. Thanks so much for
joining me on the podcast today.
>> Thank you for having me. Nice to see you
again.
>> Really looking forward to this
conversation. Uh, we met in person just
a few weeks ago at the WWDC mentioned
party. You actually spoke on a little
panel I hosted during the mansion party.
It was so fun to get yours I thought
it'd be great to have you on the podcast
so we could do a much deeper dive. You
didn't get to talk a lot on that panel
was two other people and that you people
were asking them questions a lot. But
anyhow, you you've had quite a a career
in mobile and so I wanted to go through
some of your top lessons across all
these different companies. So you were
at Coca-Cola in the Ukraine doing like
standard marketing and you got thrown
into the deep end. Your first ever
experience with a mobile app was
BetterMe and you joined as essentially
the CMO. Maybe we should start with just
a little bit of what that was like and
then we'll get into the the practical
lessons and takeaways from all these
different amazing companies you've been
at.
>> Thank you. Yes, I do think that the uh
experience in better me was a shaping
one but in the same time it is very
similar what a lot of app founders are
probably going through right now like at
that time we didn't know anything and we
were kind of like dipping our toes in
the water and this is basically what
what I see when a person launches their
app they are trying they're looking at
different angles they're trying to learn
as much as they're they can and this is
why I'm here now I want to talk about
like 10 years of experience so that
people don't make the same mistakes and
also take some lessons that I had to
live through. Some of them were painful
but this would be like as you know
better me is an amazing company that
grew so much and I would like to talk
about something that made them special
and this is not looking for the uh
stability in their performance
marketing. They're performance marketing
he heavy obviously. So when you're going
into the business what I would recommend
to you if for example you launch your
traffic you spending some money you are
like spending $100 $500 per uh day and
then you see same CPMs same CTAs you see
that like oh one user cost me $30 I'm
getting $50. Yes I have my margin I will
scale I will go further. This is bad for
you actually. because you stop trying
and you think oh my LTV or whatever it
looks great I will I'm doing everything
fine you are not doing fine you are
doing very very badly because your first
tries your first uh creatives your your
first results shouldn't be good in any
way they will be they will not be very
good uh what you need to to see in your
performance marking has there ever been
a moment when you thought wow Wow, this
is so much better than everything that
I've done before where your CPAs went
down, doubled down, when your amount of
purchases tripled in one day. This is
the moment when you know that this is
actually happening for you. If it's just
happening, it's not okay. But when it's
happening all of a sudden with one
creative, and it will happen with one
creative, one concept, one something,
that's when you think, "Oh, I kind of
made it. I kind of understand what's
what it's about now. So, never settle
for mediocracy and always always be
looking for those creatives that will
move the needle to the points where you
never expect it. You never expect it,
but when it happens, you're like, "Ah,
that's what you talked about."
>> I love the framing you started off with
that that uh all along the way, you
know, from 10 years ago till today,
there's always been change. You know,
app tracking transparency was a huge
change. you know, people who got really
good at uh UGC in the last couple years,
it was new. You had to write the
playbook and and and really it seems
like that that's where the outsiz
returns are is not in the safe like this
is what everybody's doing. It's actually
writing your own playbook and figuring
out the new thing where there is
opportunity versus just doing what's
been done before. And then I really like
that the framing of of like you
shouldn't seek out too much stability
because that means you're not swinging
for the fences and it's a swinging for
the fences that really like give you
those outside returns as well.
>> Fun fact actually you you're talking
about UGC's and the first people that
were with UGC's in the fitness uh
sphere. It did happen around 2017 and it
was banded spoons that just got into the
IPO. So like they're switching it a
little bit and getting all their traffic
and then building their company.
Obviously it's not just about that but
like for them finding those UGC angles
first really helped them a lot. So um
yeah you're right.
>> So other than just setting the
expectations of the marketing team that
you should expect some big failures and
you should expect some uncertainty and
some you know big movements. How do you
organize around this idea? And how do
you find and try weird things that are
going to give you that? And then also
maybe there's some amount of safeguards
you should put in place to not go too
crazy with it.
>> No, nothing is too crazy. And also
nothing is too like if I can say it
nothing is too ugly. There is this
famous saying like make ugly ads. I
think we invented that and I believe in
that 100% because people don't want the
TV shots at any point that they want
something that catches them on the first
glance. if you like and it is hard to do
that and now that that I'm returning to
like creative marketing a little bit I I
have to stop myself knowing this and
telling this on all the podcast all the
time that please please don't make the
prettiest don't listen to to Claude when
they like tell you which creatives to
create and then they give you a
15-second creative no don't do that
always be like first second you need to
understand what you're selling and what
you're doing this is uh Uh this is very
very important. Yes. So um guard rails
should be around really knowing that you
are not a marketer that is a Coca-Cola
marketer that sells a brand that is 200
years old that is like known by
everybody already. You are selling
something that nobody knows about
basically. And when you come to
traditional marketing actually what they
tell you first like when you're
launching a brand you should a brand you
should start with uh something that is
super about the product. So for example
you're launching juices on the market
and there has been like never been a
juice company on the market. First you
need to talk about how good they are for
your health. They they you need to talk
about how they are nutrition nutri
nutritionist how how you get nutrients
from them and then you go to happiness
and the feelings and more. So when you
start and with performance marketing we
are kind of always on this starting
point. You should be about the product
that you're selling and obviously about
the pain that you are solving for the
users. And if I can actually like talk
about it a little bit more, I want to
tell like a lot of people come to me
sometimes, not a lot of people, some
people come to me, one or two people
have come to me and asked me a question
about launching their product and a lot
of times it's they come up with the idea
and they're like, I've already hired a
developer or I am a developer. I'm vibe
coding it. I know that you are a big
vibe coder, so obviously you know what
I'm talking about. And it pains me so
much to always tell them start with
marketing first. No, you you cannot like
vip code the whole product and then hope
for it to be needed. Just start with
marketing. Sell a PDF, sell an idea,
sell something and then refund because
you don't have a product. It's okay.
just see if you if there are enough
people even interested uh in this
product because you can do something
that is very interesting for me and for
yourself and I feel it all the time. I'm
like, "Oh, not even I my husband really
likes aquariums and he thinks, wow, we
will do this apps for all these aquarium
people and it will be so popular." And
if we did marketing because I'm
obviously stopping him from chasing his
dreams, many bad wife. So if if we did
that, we would see that the audience is
very small, that it's very expensive to
bring new people to the app, and that we
would never like make the uh
monetization happen. So don't think that
your idea is bad, but always prove it
with marketing before you actually put
some money into launching something.
This is my super heartfelt advice that
also I fall into the traps all the time.
So yeah, everybody does. Well, let let
me let me push back on that because I'm
curious your thinking and maybe I'm
just, you know, naive on this front, not
having done it myself, but for an
aquarium app, would there not
potentially be a way to make that kind
of app work with UGC? Because I imagine
there's like, you know, people who are
into aquariums are very much into, you
know, aquarium related content on, you
know, Instagram and and then and
aquariums are expensive. I mean, you
know, the the the fish are expensive,
the maintenance is expensive, the fake
plants are exp like everything about
that. I I've never had an aquarium, but
I've looked at them and like it's so
expensive and and so that's maybe a
category where you can charge a lot and
then there's enough of a kind of uh
dedicated niche where you could create
content that speaks directly to that.
From your perspective, was it just too
small of an idea or do you think it's
still just too hard to reach those
people and you just couldn't charge
enough to make it worth it?
>> No, I I I do have to say thank you for
telling me that because obviously we
believed in this idea. We wanted to do
it, but we wanted to do it before Claude
and like I I even like came to Lovable,
made my first like u sketches and stuff,
but I I'm not a VIP coder at any point,
so I gave up before trying it obviously.
So, it is it is a good idea. We agree on
that. Please don't steal it. Anyone who
listens to it, please don't steal it.
But uh yeah, it is probably very doable.
Anything is doable. Let's be honest. But
we also need to understand what is the
reason for doing it. So uh if for
example you want to be making like I
don't know 20k per month so that you
just don't have to go to work a 9 to5
job. Yes, that's like an amazing idea.
But if I came with that to a VC,
I I would probably not have the LTV tok
that would be needed to like sell the
app. Could you do partnerships with uh
uh with brands and sell uh specific
products? Yes, probably a good idea.
Yes, I will do that idea. So, thank you
David very much. But what I was talking
about is that uh see like but just
because it was a good idea, you agreed
with me. If it was a not very good idea,
you would be like, "Yeah, you should
try. You should try. Of course, you're
like because we all want to support
people around us and we would be like,
"Yes, this is such a great idea." Like
this is how like Eastern Europeans and
American is super Americans are super
different because you seem to always be
supporting ideas and uh supporting
people around you and in our countries
it would be like who would need that?
Nobody would need that obviously. So
yeah, that's that's different mindsets,
but yeah, so don't don't fall into traps
by by having the support of your family.
That's also like a a big one probably.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Totally. And and I guess like what
that what that even boils down to in
your framing is even to get to that 20k
a month in profit that you would be able
to quit your 9 toive job unless you're
just like an amazing UGC or like you
know find creators that you could pay
dirt cheap or find affiliates or like
you know there are a lot of creative
ways to do it but if it were just kind
of traditional performance marketing
you'd probably be having to spend 100
200k to ek out that 20k a month now. And
and it would have to be a full-time job.
Let's be honest. Like
>> yeah, it's hard to it's hard to
bootstrap. I mean, and maybe this is
really good for people to hear who are
just starting out. Like it it is really
hard to bootstrap to that level. Uh
especially on paid because you could
just spend every dollar that comes in
into paid marketing and then you're
you're working full-time and not
actually making any money. The beauty of
subscriptions though is like if it's at
all retentive, then by the next year,
you should start cash flowing a little
better. And so then, but then you got to
think about it as like this year-long
investment where you're working full
making almost nothing to hopefully get
it off retention in year two to make it
work. So, back to kind of your original
point, it's like it is it's probably a
pretty hard app to bootstrap into uh and
would take a lot of work. Well, talking
about bootstrapping, actually the second
app that I moved to was fully
bootstrapped and when I uh joined it, it
was doing like 35k per month in traffic
with a lot of spending. So, it was quite
a challenge and it actually taught me
something that is also very important
for all the app founders and it is don't
look for a silver bullet. Don't look for
a CMO. Don't look for a person that will
save you from your own troubles. It will
happen if you meet someone great if
you're super super lucky. But most of
the times if you are the founder type,
you will figure it out in marketing
yourself and you need to put a lot of
effort into understanding marketing. You
are probably a smart person that have
understood much harder things in your
life. And please don't think that it is
it's not hard. It it it's not hard at
all to understand marketing but to feel
it with your own hands. This is
something that every founder needs to
know why I'm talking about it here
because like it it was an app called Eva
Learn English and at some point it was
number two after Dualingo and uh it has
an amazing team and um the founder he
actually was super into marketing. He
was on every marketing meeting. He was
doing it all himself. He was thinking of
creatives himself and like when I left
he actually was like well I want to do
it. I want to do it because it's also my
passion. It's my product. I want to make
sure that I talk about my product in a
way that is uh like that people will
understand it and I appreciate that
greatly because in people when they
understand that they love their product
enough to actually promote it and to
talk about it very very much. Uh and uh
so basically you should do it all
yourself on like we talked about at some
point about like the first one person uh
one person startup unicorn startup
something like that like where you don't
need anyone anymore and this is the
first sphere where like I do still think
that you need developers because that's
too hard to understand to for any normal
person sorry but I do think that
marketing is something that like
everybody is a marketer and you can
understand it as a founder you need to
understand it definitely I don't know
like uh do you agree
>> I I was thinking of an example where
you're talking um the latter CEO Greg
have been on the podcast a couple times
and that's one of the things he talked
about was that they were really
struggling with marketing and he as a
CEO was just like okay I got I am going
to figure this out and then I'll pass it
off to somebody else and I I think that
you So probably something more CEOs even
even of like bigger company today like
not just bootstrapping but even if
you're already at a fairly large company
and and you're you know running the
company or if you're a marketer at the
company you should be encouraging your
CEO or whatever that like when there's a
big hurdle the CEO should probably be
pretty hands-on trying to solve that
specific thing and this is something I I
respect a ton about Revenue Cat CEO
Jacob. It's one of the things he's done
really well over the years is when there
is a big blocker or a new thing that
like we really need to push on, he gets
really involved in a way that I think,
you know, shows the company this is a
priority. It also like engages all his
experience and knowledge and effort and
like passion to like make it work. Like
a founder is just going to have the
passion to make it work in a way that an
employee just never will. No matter how
good of an employee, there's just a
difference. And so, yeah, I I I totally
agree and and I would say not just for
bootstrapping, but you know, any CEO
when you're facing a roadblock should
should really jump on that and get into
the nitty-gritty and help be part of the
the solution. You know, it's funny when
you were talking earlier about ugly ads.
It reminded me that the the most kind of
shocking ugly ad that I saw in probably
it was probably the time you were there
at BetterMe was this like really gross
like belly fat ad.
>> It's the best one. It's the best one. I
love it so much. Yeah.
>> And that that ad, I mean, I saw it for
years after that, so it must have been
an incredibly performant ad. It was one
of those things where it really grabbed
your attention because it was almost
shocking to see this like illustration
with this like fat just hanging off the
front and and it's like to your exact
point like I vividly remember that one
specific ad from like a decade ago
because it was so like shocking and
that's kind of the point, right? The
point is that it got people's attention.
Um do do you remember that ad
specifically and then any other thoughts
online?
>> That is the best ad ever. I loved it
completely. Yes, it was invented during
the time I was there. But uh it also
means that you have a very good eye for
it because you know uh you don't
remember these skinny girls that were
working out obviously, but you do
remember something that shocks you and
that like this is this is the thing.
Yes. Uh it's completely about taking the
person out of the grid of uh like of
scrolling your uh feed and uh like
sometimes your feed is so pretty that
you need something ugly to take your
attention from it. So yes, this is this
is why it works for sure.
>> How do you think about those kind of ad
as you do become a brand though? So like
for example I was just talking about
ladder like ladder is at a point in
scale and kind of what they're trying to
do you know they partnered with a
massive influencer actually like movie
star music star and so like at their
level they wouldn't want to run that
kind of ad like when do you think you
shouldn't be doing those kind of ugly
ads when does it actually tarnish the
brand or are we just too precious about
brand everybody should be trying those
kind of ads
>> I I shouldn't say it Because what if my
future employer I hope not to have
future employers but like uh what if
they see it but brand is something like
unless you are something like I don't
know Coca-Cola brand is something that
doesn't exist and nobody cares about
your brand but you and I do agree that
it is very important for some brands to
have the uh the integrity and to like
not do certain things but you don't have
to um for like let's talk about this
particular uh example you can have
Hillary Duff doing her thing amazing
amazing ads like love it love the uh the
messaging stuff will like and at that
panel I actually asked them like do you
think it will bring you the eye that
you're hoping for and they're like well
it's a brand marketing like obviously
you cannot like do the ROI yet and
that's the thing like Nothing brandy
will ever work as good as something
performative. So you don't you don't
have to choose actually if you think
about it with meta with everything that
we are doing. You want to run um
awareness ads please be my guest like do
that spend your money it will not bring
you anything short term. If if you need
shortterm results you go performance.
You you don't say your brand you say
fitness app. to say uh whatever like
horoscope app whatever you are doing and
this way you can still do performance
marketing and then uh and have your
results and then you can afford brand
marketing but other than that yes I I
don't believe in brand marketing and I I
wish all the best to ladder obviously
but I don't think like you know you said
like oh they're so big that they are at
that point already are they though like
at which point do you become so
selfobsessed that you think that you are
now like you know the Nike or or
whatever but the Nike is playing
different game like we are playing the
uh monetization app subscription game
and like they don't have any other
choice as well like their products
wouldn't sell if you were making them
ugly they are selling the prettiness we
are selling uh function and that is
something that is different there yeah
>> I agree generally as far as I think
folks are way too precious to some brand
and think it matters and like you know
you're you're just making 10K a month on
your little side project and you're like
oh yeah like I would never do an ugly ad
and and like you said yeah and then like
oh my branding is too important and I
want to make sure the colors in the ad
align with the colors of the app and
like and and I love how you pointed out
like don't don't take Quad's advice
because Claude is just going to tell you
like brand matters and everything needs
to be pretty and the colors need to
align and like all this kind of stuff.
Uh but I do think there is a transition
point and and with latter even though he
did say you know it's it's tough to
you know determine the exact payoff but
but you know they took a huge bet
signing Duff uh as a influencer for the
app and it has already paid off and he
shared in the panel that like you know
almost immediately they saw a pretty big
influx and so at some point like maybe
maybe it's okay to to let yourself, you
know, if if it's performing and if it's
working to to let yourself kind of make
that transition, but but generally I do
think we are all too precious about
that. So like it it's good to have that
kind of push back and then then you just
have to justify too. Then you have to
like why does brand matter and what like
how is this going to pay off and are we
sure it's going to pay off and and you
have to ask yourself those kind of
questions where if you just default to
like oh no you know we need to be
careful with the brand then you're
having to justify the performance
marketing and it should really be the
opposite. I can give you couple of
examples here but like one of the big
mistakes that I did like regarding the
brand branding in solid starts for
example I came there and I was like
nobody cares like nobody thinkies but
for some people when the brand is big
enough and solid starts is a very big
brand they care a lot about what it
represents and this is where it is like
when you're talking about babies when
you're talking about like real doctors
and I was like AI baby not AI babies as
in real babies but babies made out
fruit. We are about feeding babies. We
are like fruit babies are super popular
on Instagram. I should definitely do an
ad like that. And then we saw some
feedback of like should we trust a
company that invented this like to to
feed our babies. And then like okay yes
we will do brand now because that's just
you know I I I understand that it's like
it's it's no big deal for you know in in
the grand scheme of things. the universe
wouldn't collapse if you do one ad that
isn't like in your brand voice of course
but in the same time yeah if if you are
something that is selling uh trucks
maybe it's not good to sell it with uh I
don't know uh AI
strawberries I don't know whatever so
basically like see what you're selling
and if uh if making ugly um applies to
it but also don't assume that it doesn't
apply just because you love your brand
so much the brand that only exists in
the heads of you, your family, and some
of your employers employees, not even
all of them.
>> Yeah. Well, that that was a really fun
digression. I I think people will enjoy
that that push back on on both sides.
Um, so what was the next philosophy you
learned at EBAT? This one is actually
very uh very applicable now when you see
that a lot of people they don't use
their strengths like couple of people
came to me at some point and they were
from different countries they were from
Lithuania they were from India they were
from like different markets and they're
like oh help us grow and what they want
to do first is to go America of course
let's let's start with the US market
because it it has like a lot of uh cash
value. It is right but in the same time
you should look first at what you you
know best. So Babel uh a great example
uh what's their name? Uh Blinkist also
like they started with Germany and they
are super big in Germany and they're
getting the same results as Germany in
Germany as some people are getting in
the US which is like what 10 times
bigger. So if you have a uh benefit of
knowing some local market better,
definitely use it because this is what
Eva did. Like it was very good in
speaking their native language and they
started this like super funny, super
whimsical app that everybody in their
local country liked. Then they grew it
to all their other languages. But the
actual lesson here is not that. The
actual lesson here is the world is
really really big and with current AI
when you can translate any service like
in 3 hours into any languages why don't
you try different languages why don't
you try localization because this is
something that can like double your
income just by trying let's be honest
and there are markets that like if you
go to conferences you know that
everybody is talking about like oh go to
Japan they're so uh so rich and uh they
will bring you a lot of money. It's kind
of hard. It's kind of hard to go to
Japan because they have very like local
things but at the same time there are a
lot of countries that are that are just
as Americanized Europeanized
can even say that but it's okay. Yeah.
So that where you can find a lot of uh
benefits and uh for yourself. So
localization is something I would
definitely bet on if I had to join any
company. And I see it like also
happening in a lot of companies when
when one door closes, you know, the
other ones open. Uh what we found, for
example, in my last company, it was that
like testing your ads, testing your ads
is super important. You need to test
like 500 ads per per week. And if you do
that uh on US CPMs, you will definitely
go broke. But if you do that with
countries that have the similar uh
similar conversion rates like I don't
know Indonesia and you will see the same
results for the same tests for $10 a day
instead of $1,000 per day. This is where
you can actually help yourself scale in
the US as well by testing in different
locals. That's for sure.
>> Any any top um fails or lessons from
localization? I know and you kind of
hinted at it with Japan. Uh, and we've
talked about this on the podcast a few
times now that certain markets you
really do have to kind of understand the
local customs. Like they need to feel
like you understand them. You almost in
Japan almost have to have a local like
partner or even a partner agency to to
not just localize the text in the app,
but localize the kind of images you use,
the kind of payroll you do. Uh, so any
other top lessons on localization?
I I I can say that in replica we did
make a big bet on Japan. We even have
like person that knew Japanese in the in
the team and we we like did the actual
localization like the culturalization of
the app didn't work in any way because
uh it is harder than we think but in the
same time there are like so many good
examples like you wouldn't think like
Turkey is the biggest market right now.
Who would have thought like who thinks
about Turkey when they are not going on
a vacation? But still it it is
converging in a lot of ways. So don't go
hard. Don't go go countries you cannot
understand obviously but don't go hard
on countries you cannot understand if
it's not like something like I would
never probably be able to understand
Taiwanese people for example but uh in
the same time um I sell I sell stuff
there but I do understand that it's a
fraction of what it could be if I
actually understand the culture and it's
okay and you know uh I don't know if you
have something to say here but I want to
also like add from my personal
experience and like why I came to the
states in the first place was to learn
different cultures of the people and uh
here you can actually see how different
people are but in the same time how sane
people are for example you wouldn't
think but like my friend is Korean and
she
>> has the same like childhood traumas as
me because like the parents are you know
the same level of harshness and like it
it is easier for example for us to talk
to people from from Central America for
example because they also have you know
they they didn't have this happy
childhood that everybody thinks about.
So especially when you're working like
to solve people's problems like all the
problems come from childhood. So like
understanding those small things like
this is this is kind of important. Yes.
That that's why that's my main lesson on
localization. Don't even try it but also
try it very very much. I love the way
you frame things and that that's a great
lesson too as far as like don't just
look for the differences, look for the
similarities. That's that's a really
great framing is to go in and understand
how those countries are similar, not
just how they're different. Um, so after
EBA, you ended up at PA, the parent
company of Flow, which I think everybody
listening to the podcast should know.
It's one of the biggest apps in the
world right now. Uh, what are some of
the lessons you you learned there at
Pula? What I learned there was more
about the culture and like how you build
big companies. And um the thing I want
to say here um is actually why on this
podcast as well is that they have a very
good culture of sharing things. So you
would have a lot of companies coming
together and just sharing like today we
did this test this test performed this
way. you can like steal this test and uh
localize it and like uh put it in your
app and see how it works and sharing
doesn't mean that you are losing
something. It always means that you are
gaining something. So I would actually
tell to more marketers like share your
wins. It doesn't mean that everybody
will get the same results because no
matter what we are sharing, no matter
how we are doing it, it's so much
different from industry to industry. It
just keeps your ju creative juices
flowing. And this is what we actually
need because uh I I think that like at
some point someone somewhere uh added a
blink on the continue button, you know,
the the like the
Yeah. And and turned out it increases
your conversion. And uh these ideas that
don't come to just one hat and this is
why my my dream goal for like this is
why I this is what I talk about uh with
every revenue catch representative out
there that we should have like a camp
for marketers where we work on one
problem and like actually try to solve
it because this will be beneficial for
every company actually in the world.
This is this is why we are like not
failing but we are as as a uh industry
we are not growing fast enough because
everybody is so silent. If we were doing
it all together if like every company in
America as well like if we were trying
to erase it all to like to to grow it
all together it will be much bigger
results. But of course, of course, there
are so many people that come to
presentations and don't show the be
their best creatives because no, don't
show like like don't show your best uh
presentations like your best
experiments. That is Like you
shouldn't do that. You should share and
u the faster we we iterate the faster we
grow. That that is the but also just
have a peer group. just have a peer
group where you can like set up this
weekly calls and say, "Oh, I tested
this. How did it go?" Because we met at
the mansion party and one of the things
about it was that there were no nobody
selling anything and you could actually
talk about like with app founders and it
is such a great conversation where when
you actually get deep into into like
what works, what doesn't work. Like you
see like people on the on the bleachers
just you know just roasting each other's
apps and it is it is amazing experience
as well because how often do you see
someone who who like knows what they're
talking about actually take a look at
what you're doing because no company has
enough budget to to hire two CMOs. Let's
call it that. Yeah. So that that's my
like uh main thing. Just just share.
It's okay. Uh, I I love that idea of of
doing some kind of like summits or or
camp or I even the camp framing is fun.
Like rent a rent a huge Airbnb and bring
15 people from different apps in and
solve some major problems over over a
weekend and then share share some of the
results with with the rest of the
industry. That's fantastic. I'll I'll uh
run that up the chain and see if Revy
Cat can be the one to to do something
like that. Sub club sponsored
marketer camp and and do exactly that.
But but that was kind of the point of
the mansion party and a lot of the
events that we do try and do is to get
people together and have those
conversations. But to your point, you
know, finding those kind of communities
across the industry and it is tough when
you know you obviously wouldn't want to
share your best stuff with your
competitor, but they probably see it
anyway because they can just look at the
meta ad. But, you know, find three or
four apps that that are adjacent to
yours that where you can share and and
that can be a really powerful thing. And
and what was cool with PTA is because it
was portfolio company that had a lot of
different apps, you were all kind of
aligned to make money for PTA and so you
could share those things more easily
amongst each other. Um, and so that's a
really cool thing. What what was
something else you learned with your
time at Alta? So there are like and as
as a big company obviously they they
have the budgets to hire like really
good consultants and you know we did
have people come to to the company
talking about like uh marketing at a
different level and like people that are
thinking ahead and this is what I
noticed also about some other companies
that I worked in like Hicksfield like
Replica like like Paul as well they have
ideas that will be working in 5 years
from now. So it was 2021 when I was
there and at that point there there was
no no chip or like some chip it was chip
2.0 only in America as well and then
there was like very very basic AI and at
that point they started Zing which is
like a AI training app. Uh when like and
when you think about it there was
nothing there. It was obviously like a
scam, not scam like but they were like
okay in 5 years AI will be there. We
will be ready. We will be already
positioned on the market as an AI
company and it will be okay. The same
thing with like Hixold when I talked to
the founder of it like and he told me
like in like next year AI agents will be
a thing. I'm like I don't know what AI
agents are but if you say so okay. And
what do you know like next year AI
agents agents are a thing and so this I
don't know how to become a visionary.
I'm not a visionary but at the same time
think about what doesn't exist now and
what might exist in the future and and
go that way. This is something that
somehow you need to do. Uh maybe like do
tarot tarot cards or something like see
the future and then go that way. That's
that's my main idea here. Yeah. No, I
really like that. It's like looking to
the future and and right now is a really
great moment where you know it does feel
like for some tasks AI is too expensive
but it's those tasks that in two years
you know as AI continues to get smarter
and then the current models get cheaper
maybe it is. And so like right now is a
great time to take that exact advice and
figure out like what's going to work in
two years that doesn't work today and
build toward that. And you know for some
companies it's it's also like accepting
lower margins and you know accepting
higher cash burn if you've got venture
capital to burn today because in two
years it will work. So that's really
good advice. Um and speaking of all this
AI stuff, you did spend some time at
Higsfield. What were what was your top
lesson at Higsfield?
>> Yeah, Hicksfield it was an amazing
experience. this was like like looking
in the future and that's that's also the
thing that you just talked about like
when we started it was too early for the
market. It was a video model and at that
point it looked like you know like uh
what's his name? Uh
who who was eating pasta eating
spaghetti? Yeah. Eating spaghetti. Yeah.
On on the earlier versions. And then
like we did understand that in a year
like in a couple of years and it did
turn out in a year like it will be much
much better. But we came to all these
VCs or we came to all these
presentations talking about like how it
will be the future and they looked at
what was there now and they were like oh
no I don't think so. And now I think
they're biting their lips so hard for
not investing earlier in Hicksfield. So
that's uh that was an interesting one.
But overall what I can say about that
like they are
a very special team. So um um they were
founded by people that obviously won um
physics olympiads and like very very
very smart people. But besides being
smart, what made them super different
from everybody else is that they they
could sleep in the office. They worked
17 hours per day. They made all the
people like work 17 hours per day. But
the people that were there, the core
team, they were keen to do it. This is
their opportunity and they took this
opportunity. They are now like super
rich people as well. So it was the first
time where I saw someone grind that
hard. Like at all the other companies
like you would see a founder grind or
you would see like someone being or or
not even a founder. Sometimes founders
are like, "Oh, I will go surf with Bali
or something." And when you see someone
who is engaged in a way that like
everybody in the team is working 12
hours a day or whatever time a day and
also they officially have like six uh
days per week work days, whatever you
call it. Yeah. So that's too much for
everyone. Like would I want to work that
at my age? Probably not. But in the same
time with the uh product being so
interesting, so good, so uh so ahead of
everyone else maybe you need to. And you
know after that company I actually
started to work more like in in my next
companies because I'm like while you are
sleeping the other ones are shipping
releases and I'm starting to push
everyone and obviously I see a lot of
push back because like oh you know we
are Gen Z we we want our comfort. We are
not used to suffering and uh you know as
a millennial I'm used to suffering and
as like as we all know what it takes to
like build a career and we all know what
it takes to like become successful and
to to remember that even when you
decided to not remember that that's
that's kind of important. So uh when you
work really hard where when you are
resilient you will get where you want to
be. That's that's the main lesson I
think because they are now above
everybody else. I I love them so much.
Also great service. I I cannot promote
them enough. Sorry. Like if you if you
need a a UGC like I you know it's not
even about like loving them as a
company. It's about uh trying the
product and being like oh AI can do that
now. Because before like I was using
clink for example and I would give them
the picture and it would put it into
thing. I had to think about everything.
And here just just as an example, I was
I gave them the app logo and I created
an avatar for a UGC person. I didn't put
any prompting. I didn't put like even
the texting and it just gave me a
perfect UGC and that didn't even look
like UGC. And I'm like, is this the
future? Are we in the future now?
because because that's
you know I I still react to it as a
person who should be used to it but I'm
not used to it and uh yeah that's that's
why if you work 16 hours a day people
will talk about like that about your
product. This is why I don't believe in
like you know working working two jobs
or like working uh part-time on your own
project.
>> It's tough. I mean, as a as a father of
four and you I'm almost 50 years old, I
I can't anymore and and that's almost
like depressing. But if I think back,
you know, when I was in my 20s, I
actually worked at a recording studio
and that's what I studied in college and
and that's what my passion was,
recording. And that's exactly what I did
was like I went to work at noon uh
because musicians stay up late and sleep
in by necessity oftent times because
they're playing at clubs till 2:00 a.m.
or whatever. And so that that's just
their their like natural cycle. And so
we would work from noon till like 2 3 4
a.m. go home, go to bed, wake up, and
come back at noon and do it all over
again for weeks on end to make an album.
I had so much fun doing that. when when
it's something you're passionate about,
when you really care about what's going
on, when you're doing something
meaningful,
uh it's very different than just, you
know, being an employee where the boss
is cracking the whip and it's just
always so stressful. like they I I I
don't think enough people in those kind
of conversations about like founder mode
and grinding and all that kind of stuff
have maybe just not had that kind of
experience of of being so passionate
about something and young enough to like
make it happen and not having kids and
you know there are different life
situations. But but it's a really good
point and if you're if you're in that
position where you can grind and you're
super passionate and excited like you do
often see outsized results from those
kind of people in those kind of
situations versus the like employees
where you're cracking the whip to work
10 hours a day. Um and that that just
doesn't work. And I think you can have
great outcomes with with both but it's
just a different mentality. It's a
different situation. So if you can it's
pretty amazing. So after Paula, you
ended up at Replica. Uh what were some
of your lessons from from your time
there?
>> Uh I want to talk about both Replica
experience and solid stars experience in
the same one uh in the same way because
they are completely different apps
obviously but they are in a way same
because they both had huge organic and
this is what everybody dreams about
obviously like I want to be growing
organic. wanted to bring me money
without spending any dollar on paid ads
and this is the goal and now I can see
that like that goal is pretty achievable
let's be not pretty achievable if you
put a lot of like effort on it obviously
there is no magic pill to go viral
obviously but if you find something that
doesn't exist yet this is where your
potential for organic is huge and this
is why I uh I will talk about it later
but like This is why finding something
unique is like 50% of your success. And
uh with both these apps uh it was very
fun experience to have just money
flowing in without and you didn't have
to like rely only on being profitable
dayto-day uh to uh to actually grow the
company. But the things that like but it
is a double age sword and if you think
that like it will make you super happy
to have huge organics at some point it
will play super against you because you
will see that uh for example you start
with with the US because you know
English and you you you start you are in
American uh person and there is no niche
that would uh cover all the people that
live. So you need to find your niche and
at some point your niche will be all
your Instagram following, Tik Tok
following like everybody who could have
joined like in 5 years they will all
join and uh you will see that your
organic stagnates and for example you
will be like oh I want to sell my
company I want to show them great
results but your organic is already like
very stable and you cannot sell you
cannot show like growth. of you are
like, "Oh, I will go into paid
marketing. I will uh like because
because my product is so good, everybody
likes it and uh like I I can get even
more money by promoting it.
50% of the time it will be cannibalizing
cannibalization and uh you will not know
what to do with it. And if at any point
you will you will have like investors
and people pushing you to grow, it will
be very very hard to grow without uh
without just bringing in the same money
but spending more. And I I've noticed it
a couple of times now. This is like a
sad uh sad story, sad lesson. But it is
a very nice feeling at first, but then
you have to think about the future.
Always think like what will be happening
five years ahead. So with replica it was
fun because it was al also like super
ahead of its time and uh in five years
we didn't know that it would become
super commodity wise because super
commodity because JGBT will be there and
everybody will be doing this rappers and
stuff. So you cannot predict that all
this organic will for example drop and
you can like when you're building
performance marketing performance is
more or less stable. You see every day
what you're getting you are adjusting.
You are obviously like stressed out
every day but at the same time you kind
of can influence it with organic you
cannot influence it per se. So what you
need to do you're like okay Julie you
just told a situation what's what's the
solution for it? Yes. So what you need
to do is when you start a brand start
with perform performance marketing as
well because it will definitely help you
grow your organic as well. So every ad
that you're showing on Tik Tok or on
Facebook, it is bringing you new
subscribers. And for example, with Eva
where we have like a 10 million
Instagram, probably probably less
probably like 7 million Instagram. It
was just a small idea and we started it
and we started getting a lot of um
people from the ads that were just
coming for free. And then when you
became like a big Instagram account, you
became uh like you're also organically.
it it grew up your organic. So
is like a lot of people are thinking
like is PR important? Is putting out
like things on tech crunch and uh I
don't know how I don't know PR so I
don't know like is going on TV important
it is not for your performance but in
the end like it will bring you a lot of
organic but it is all only possible if
you have something unique to offer to
people and that's it. So if you're doing
a time tracker, please don't worry about
organic at any point or about
canibilization or like a clear for your
app. No, this is this will not be
happening. Uh the same as like branding
won't be happening. But if you are
something unique like an aquarium app
that doesn't exist anymore yet doesn't
exist yet. uh then uh then obviously you
can think about organic and uh it is
quite easy to do like uh and also what
who you need to uh who I met on the
mansion party is the founder of minutes
app a great guy who is very good in
bringing organic traffic maybe you
should have him on your podcast he like
gave me a master class on that and I'm
like oh so doing organic is pretty easy
actually so that's that's something you
should definitely look into for uh yeah,
look forward for uh David's new podcast.
>> Yeah, that's such great framing around
organic that you you really do need to
have something I the reason people
share, the reason word of mouth happens,
the reason you press, the reason UGC can
go viral and Cali is a great example of
this is that it was so visual that you
could take a picture. It was new. It was
unique. And you know, I imagine now, you
know, three or four years on, those ads
didn't perform as well because now every
calorie app has that same standard
functionality. And so even with the
uniqueness and it's kind of to your
point like organic at some point does
start to slow down. You saturate your
market. You know, competitors come in,
the uniqueness is no longer unique. And
and so all those factors in play, you
need to be looking around a corner at
what's next and not just relying on the
same playbook for years. And appsource
search is the one area that if you're a
utility and you've locked in that number
one spot, those kind of things really
hard to accomplish and and the
algorithms seem to favor older apps. So
it's almost more hard than it ever been
to capture ASO. But that's one of the
examples of organic that just seems to
keep trucking along that people I mean
maybe you know over time trends shift
and and people like right now there are
a bunch of GLP1 apps and people are
searching GLP1s well at some point um
you know it'll just be more commonplace
and and the trend will slow down and
people won't be searching that as much
or whatever but yeah that's one area
where man it's the one organic channel
that just seems to just deliver deliver
for years on end for some apps.
I I have a funny story actually about uh
when Chip came out um and they didn't
have their own because they were doing
it with you actually not because they
were doing it with you but like before
they started doing it with you uh they
uh like JDP was already word of mouth
but they uh there were a lot of rappers
that were uh released that most of them
were Turkish for some reason as well and
now they are still like number one not
number one but like super super high on
that and we talked to them at some point
and a lot of people wanted to uh to play
on that and like okay I will do my own
chip rapper I will be like your your
personal assistant whatever whatever
because they saw that it was number one
in the store for for for these apps but
the fun fun moment was that they
actually got that initial install influx
and they solidified their first place on
the store and all of their traffic was
organic. And when you try to like
actually replicate their monetization
strategy, their like pay walls and
stuff, it didn't matter at all because
they weren't getting money from there.
Like they they didn't know what to do
with that as well. They couldn't even
sell it because they that's all just
dumb luck. But we as a people who who
don't know that we are like, "Oh, they
must they must be making a lot of money.
So we if we replicate it, maybe we will
get the same." No. No. But yes. So is uh
something you want to get into for sure.
But also
I I I I look at uh Steve Young the like
all the time and he has his like ASO
agency and I'm like the work is so
mysterious mysterious and not not like I
cannot understand what they're doing
that it is working for them. But if you
know someone who is ready to like spend
all their days looking for uh keywords
and stuff, yeah, definitely be friends
with that person because it's a very
interesting topic to I'm I'm I'm at
that topic.
>> All right. Any other top lessons from
your time at replica and folk charts?
>> I was hired in a lot of companies, you
know, like a recruiter reached out and
they're looking for like a CMO and I'm
like, okay, available, not available,
blah blah. And um and now also like in
my company I'm also looking for some
people and I'm also just like I'm just
looking for someone and just looking for
someone is not as cool as having to work
with people that are actually super I
would say almost religious about what
they do like in replica when you have
people that were like ML and ML wasn't
like a a super popular thing like we
will we will think of LLMs we will we
will test that, we will know what to do.
And you're like, "Okay, you have a super
great app on the market." Because
because of that, because at that point,
like we literally got millions of
messages saying that like you have a
person in in Ohio that is responding to
me, this is not real. But no, it wasn't
a land that was that good. Uh and uh
with sols that's like 10 times higher
because everybody on that team is keen
on uh baby lew weing and on feeding
babies and I I know their old stories
and it's it's crazy to think that each
one of them like messaged the founder
being like I'm so passionate about that
that I want to be on your team no matter
what. And this is where you see the
results being so amazing because like if
I'm just doing my job, I'm just doing my
job. I clock in, clock out. If you have
a person that is passionate about it,
that is already a super beneficial thing
for your team. But if you have 20 people
that are just about that, this is this
can change. This is why solid start
starts is actually changing the whole
baby leaning like cate not even category
like the the the baby leaning in the USA
in the world like they're changing the
way that like people start allergens and
therefore there are less allergic people
in the world. That is super super
important. And when when I grow up, I
really want to have a team of people
that will be super interested in what
they're doing. I think what the market
is actually lacking because I'm a little
bit in a mental health space right now,
the market is lacking an app, for
example, that we made will be made by
actual doctors. the team of doctors, the
team of doctors that understand what
what this whole thing is about because
every app that is in the market is just
created by someone who went to therapy
once or twice and it is already like
helping. But what would happen if people
would actually start thinking about how
to make it more affordable, not more
affordable, more uh access accessible to
people. And uh this is my like personal
pain obviously that there are so many
people that start their apps uh so many
companies that now are like oh we will
start another app because we know that
somebody is getting money from it. And I
see that for example with solid stars
there were people that would just like
put u GPT rapper again in the app and be
like yes like baby le with chbt and
you're reading what it uh offers and you
understand that it's bad it's bad for
your baby it's bad for for what you are
doing and you're like why would you not
consider the effect of your action you
know and this is why I would like like
for more people to not launch shitty
apps and just think about what they're
doing for Yeah. And I I understand we
all want an extra 5k. Yes. Okay. Like
that that would be nice. You would go to
a uh taco trip, but like if you will
harm people by doing that, is it worth
it? Probably. Yes. Of course. 5K. I
mean, yeah, sure. Sure it was. But uh
yeah, I mean uh I I hope that with time
like and this is what we are seeing now
with uh V coding making it all very
accessible and like everybody can launch
any app now like there will be a lot of
apps that will flood the market and you
know the numbers like of how many apps
are being released every day and I I am
pretty sure that none of them are the to
the standards of what we want them to
be. So I do hope that still the
investors will not only invest in like
you know AI stuff but they will also
invest into something that will be of
good quality and like we'll have medical
teams, professional teams whatever
behind it and it will change the future
of the humanity. You know we are here to
be to make a greater world as well.
Speaking of of making the world a better
place, you recently did an interview
that I I stumbled upon preparing for the
podcast uh where you you called the end
of Black Hat Growth. Uh so I'd love to
hear your thoughts on what Black Hat
growth is and like why it should end or
is ending.
So you obviously know about what's
happening in the industry and how like
even the government is now against
everything that is happening with uh
subscriptionbased quizzes. Let's call
them that. And the problem is that it
got too far. So when it started it
became a great way to to not worry about
it and this was only that like you try
that you get the results you don't pay
the commission to Apple amazing great
but then like a little bit of greed came
in and we are all greedy it's okay to be
greedy obviously what is not okay is to
um to make it on purpose that's that's
the whole thing because what started was
like Oh, what what if we actually like
do this? It started with how can it
ended up with how can uh we actually lie
to the users so they don't don't
understand that uh they were lied to and
that it hurt the whole industry. I think
I I don't like the results of it because
with some companies they they did it or
like they did it to some sorts and it
was okay and now they're being hurt as
well as companies that were just doing
super like it almost became as bad as
sweep stakes even though like it's
completely different like you know it's
a completely different thing like you
you don't understand what you're signing
you don't understand what you're
subscribing to and that's not okay and I
know that for for a lot of time like a
lot of big companies that were like that
started this then like understood what
they've done. They've been trying to go
back. They've been trying to like okay
now we send uh like emails saying this
is the uh so that like some people just
want to not know the what they're
subscribing to. Let's be honest, there
were so many people that were like start
free trial. they uh uh uh like you know
on the apps like start free trial then
they confirm that it will take money
from them and then they say well I
didn't know it will take my money
obviously some people just want to not
notice things but like this is when like
the uh with those quizzes they started
sending emails they starting like
showing uh full prices as well but in
the same time everybody else who got on
the market who who tried to like uh make
it work for them they're like oh what if
we don't say the full price, what if it
we only say like price per day or
something like that and it it hurt the
whole market. It it's not okay. But in
the same time, some people are being
punished while some people are still
doing that and they're not getting
anything and they also don't don't read
the room, I think, because obviously
they are now benefiting from it and
there is almost no reason for for for
government to come for them because
they're too small. They they don't care
too much. But they should just be
ashamed of themselves. As a marketer, I
I do understand this thrill of like how
else can I sell? And like if you think
about if you think about bad things that
anyone can do and if you brainstorm
about it, there are so many things that
you can do obviously, but it's important
not to play these games. But in the same
time, I was in a lot of apps and a lot
of the times Apple just deleted the app
from the store for some uh blackhead
tactics for example and then they
obviously came back. It wasn't like a
blackhead tactic per se. And then I go
to all these conferences where people
are knowledge sharing and I'm like we
got deleted from the store from this
like last month. What is happening? And
I'm talking about they're like no no
everything is okay there. So the the
standards don't exist. They try to like
even even talking about like the uh
payroll standards for uh app store. They
have the whole like article about that.
Can you understand from article from the
article what can be done and what cannot
be done? No, you cannot. And like
playing these games is uh is another
like form of sport. Like that's why I
don't go to the gym because you have to
play this game. It is really hard to
know when you've crossed that line and
then there's probably a little bit of
the kind of boiling the frog where you
know I mean I've even thought about this
some of the things we've talked about on
the podcast before even from like
Dolingo Dolingo is the one who kind of
popularized the or at least they're the
first ones I've heard it from tribe for
$0 and zero cents like the big dollar
sign 0.0000 00 like is that black hat?
Like you're the the biggest like CTA
says $0 and 0, but it is actually going
to charge you a subscription. Like was
it clear enough on the rest of the page
that they were going to be charged a
subscription? And this something like
Duolingo, a $5 billion like publicly
traded company was doing. There are
things like that could be so subtle, but
then there are other things that aren't.
And this is kind of what what your point
was and a perfect example. Well, I think
I've shared it on the podcast before,
but my wife did one of those funnel that
you were talking about on the web where,
you know, Apple's not scrutinizing it at
all and there is kind of the wild wild
west. And the technique they used, which
I I think, you know, everybody's clamped
down on from like Apple Pay to Stripe
and others, is that she went through
this whole flow and I think it was like
a um a dieting app or something like
that. And so she, you know, you get 60
questions in, you've got your sunk cost
fallacy, and then it's like, um, hey,
you can get your plan for a dollar. And
she's like, okay, cool. And then she
authorized, uh, Apple Pay for a dollar.
And then it takes her through a whole
another flow where it was like, do you
want to add on this PDF? Do you want to
add? Well, she wasn't reading. She was
just trying to like get to like, where's
my plan? I paid a dollar for this plan.
Let me get to the plan. And so she was
just continue continue critique. And
again, the boiling the frog, it's like
it was super effective. I'm sure you the
companies doing things like that were
were printing money handover fist
because and the reason we I ended up
figuring out about it is I looked at my
credit card and it was like $350 or $400
that he ended up charging.
>> And I was like, "Hey, you know, sweetie,
just checking in like you know, was this
like authorized? like if it's something
like you know if this is like a really
great plan and like you know you're
getting personal they should send you
one for that much money I had people
expectations it's just like what like
what do you mean like I only authorized
a dollar and then that's when I went
back through and I did the whole quid
funnel myself and I found that pattern
and you know I can see the little
logical steps of like oh well like that
the $1 thing works really well and then
like oh but we we say on there that like
you know but it's in fine print and
people don't read and so like you can
justify it like well it's their fault
because they didn't read the fine print
but then really is it their fault for
not doing fine reading the fine print or
>> so bad yeah but you know at some point
in apps I was like if you can scam me
into paying like you are good enough you
deserve that money but with that one no
because like you need to be good enough
for Apple but but think and here you
don't need to be good enough. You can
just take 300. But that's crazy money.
Yeah.
>> It was one of those situations where she
contacted support and said, you know, I
want a refund. And they said, well, our
terms and conditions are you have to
give it 30 days before you get a refund.
And she was like, "No, wait. Like, you
scam me." And I think we ended up
getting like half of it back. And then I
meant to do a charge back, which like
that is the best way to handle those is
just do a charge back because it
punishes them more than than especially
if if the support is not responsive in
those ways. Yeah, it it was uh it was a
pretty frustrating experience. That's
why I wanted to bring up that post is
like I I do think it's it's hard as a
marketer
to know when you're crossing that line
and and sometimes you just slowly kind
of move more and more in a direction and
really take a step back. You're like,
"Wait a minute. What am I doing here?
>> You're making a lot of money apparently.
Yeah,
>> making a lot of money but maybe not
sleeping as well at night when you
realize it." And and I hope that that's
the way uh people end up feeling about
it. But I I think it's great to like
talk about these things more. And so as
you know, since you brought that up in
in a interview, I thought it'd be great
to to chat. And so I think it it'd be a
really interesting thing for folks to to
think about and kind of take your
perspective and some examples we gave
and stuff of what does feel like it it
pretty far across the line. But as we
wrap up, this has gone uh so long. Um
but I did want to still do our lightning
round. So what's the most impactful
experiment or change or something that
you implemented this year? Your biggest
win?
>> I would say localization. I would bet on
it like on o over everything else.
That's the way to open markets that you
have never uh took money from. And
>> what is the worst experiment the the the
uh biggest fail of the past year that
you learned from? I would say that
starting too many products, uh starting
too many pots, boiling water pots,
whatever, like doing too many projects
is too hard. So I I recently joined a
team where like they had three apps in
the same time and they were trying to do
it all in the same time. And that's
something that like no matter how many
people you have, no matter how many like
uh ideas you have, good ideas, bad
ideas, how similar even the projects
are, you cannot put enough attention to
them. And I've seen a lot of teams that
are like, "Oh, we had another great
idea. We had another great idea. We will
start it right now because it cost
nothing to like develop it because we
already have the developer on uh
salary." No, no, don't do that. In order
to not make mistakes, you need to
prioritize one thing. And you need to
literally treat it like a war room where
every day you come in, you're like,
"What are we doing today?" If you want
to to scale, if you want to not fail,
that is like the biggest lesson that I
learned that don't let anything go like
like, "Oh, it's the same like you scaled
one app, you can do another app." No,
no, it's it's not like that.
>> I I feel seen by cutting two different
apps right now. I'm not doing any
marketing for the app I already
released. I've got I've got too many.
It's It's an exciting time bud coding,
you know, where I can spin out apps
without having to rely on a developer.
But I'm I'm falling exactly into that
trap. And a year from now, I will
probably say my biggest fail of the year
was taking out too many projects.
>> But also, if if vibe coding is what
drives you, why do you need to do
marketing? You know, that that's the
whole thing. It's about doing what you
like. And my main uh task for the summer
is to try to do more things that make me
feel alive. And if that's VIP coding for
you, don't don't even care about
marketing. It will you will hire a good
agency, you will hire a good SMO, and it
will all happen. Yeah.
>> All right. Last question. Growth would
be easier if
>> it would be much easier if if growth
that I have to do would happen in blue
markets instead of red markets. Because
if you're entering a red market, it's
crazy. You cannot do it. I like I
haven't entered a red market in a long
time. So now that I'm back into it, I'm
like, how are people even surviving? How
like I I do understand why like the same
people are in the industry because it's
so hard to make it right now if you
don't have a unique product that you're
working on. So don't go chasing
waterfalls. No, go chasing waterfalls.
Don't stick to the lakes. And and what
you mean by red market is or red ocean
is uh a cry crowded I was looking it up
um to to to to say it more succinctly is
it represents a crowded highly
competitive existing market. So, if
you're you're building the, you know,
2000th uh food scanning app that Kelli
approved the market for, if you're
building yet another AI noteaker, that
is very much a a red ocean um market
where you just face so much competition.
It's so hard right now.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I like, as I said, I'm
trying mental health and it's mental out
there. Yeah. You can you just cannot do
that. Yeah.
>> Oh, wow. But I mean this is where I
think there there are still some
opportunities and Cali proved this. It's
like you would have thought five years
ago that calorie counting was a red
ocean market. It was so competitive, so
hard. I thought the same with ladder
when I first met the ladder team. I was
like, "Oh no, you're building a fitness
app. Like it's such a brutal market.
It's so hard." Um, but if you have that
unique spin and you have that unique
value prop and it's defensible, that's
the hardest thing today is like if
people are just going to rip it off like
and and for Calai really it wasn't the
product itself that was defensible. It
was the hustle and the marketing that
was defensible is that they were just
able to like out execute um and do it so
quickly that they were able to grow so
so quick and be that de facto player
even as the competition rushed in. Uh so
yeah it's tough it is tough out there
>> definitely but in the same time you
enter those markets because you know
that there is money there because like
in 2017 we thought there was no no place
on like for another fitness app on the
market and like by by this time there
are companies bigger than better me that
uh originated from the same source and
still there is enough space for
everyone. So, I think with mental health
or with any other niche, like it's the
same when it's big enough, you can play
there for as long as you want. Yeah.
>> Yeah, for sure. Well, this has been such
a fun conversation. As we wrap up
though, um I do want to share with
people on July 30th, we are going to do
a live stream on YouTube with Ulia. So,
I haven't talked about this on the
podcast very much, but we're now doing
live streams every Thursday. And the
reason I've been doing them is because
I've had so many people over the years
say they love the podcast, but they're
sitting in their car just shouting
through the void like what about this or
what about that? And so this is the
perfect opportunity if you've been
listening to this podcast and you're
like oh that was a really great point
but what about this or like I want to
challenge you in that way or whatever.
this is your opportunity and and if
you're listening to this after July
30th, it's your opportunity to go get
even more insights from Ulia and and see
what kind of questions people asked on
the live stream. Um but yeah, at 9:00
a.m. Pacific time, 1800 Central European
time, we will be live on YouTube July
30th. Uh so really excited that you
agreed to do that and this is going to
be our first time to actually have a
podcast guest so quickly after the
podcast is released on the live stream.
So should be a ton of fun. Please bring
all your questions. I love answering
questions, especially tough ones.
>> Awesome. Thank you so much for joining
me. Was there anything you wanted to
share as we're wrapping up? Any um jobs
you're hiring for you want to shout out
or anything our audience can do from
you?
>> I think I'm okay. Thank you so much for
having me and uh this was a very fun
conversation. You you are amazing as an
interviewer.
>> Thanks. It was so fun having you. I
thought there's a lot of great insights
in there. So, thank you.
>> Thanks so much for listening. If you
have a minute, please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.